Finding Aid for the Gilbert A. Harrison collection of material by and relating to Gertrude Stein LSC.2108
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Articles about Gertrude Stein and/or Alice B. Toklas
  - "Gertrude Stein in France," Vogue, (July 1, 1942).; pp.60-61, 70. (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Brinnin, John Malcolm. "Gertrude Stein in Paris," The Atlantic, vol.204, no.3, (September 1959).; pp.34-40. (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - [Cartoon by Booth], The New Yorker, (October 7, 1972).; p.46. (Box 5, Folder 4)
    re A rose is a rose is a rose is a rose.
  - Chase, Mary Ellen. "Five literary portraits," The Massachusetts Review, vol.3, no.3, (Spring 1962).; pp.511-516. (Box 5, Folder 5)
    Chase's impressions of Sara Orne Jewett, Gertrude Stein, Dorothy Sayers, Rose Macauley, Willa Cather.
  - Coffelt, Beth. "The incredible Stein influence," California Living Magazine, (August 29, 1971).; pp.14-15, 17-22. Clipping. (Box 5, Folder 6)
    California Living is part of the San Francisco Sunday Examiner & Herald.
  - "The grave of Alice B. Toklas," Esquire, (January).; pp.90-103, 121-124. Clipping. (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - "Always Gtrde Stein," Southwest Review, vol.34, no.3, (Summer 1949).; pp.254-256. (Box 5, Folder 8)
    Cover photograph: Gertrude Stein by Carl Van Vechten. Bilignin, June 13, 1934.
  - "Gertrude Stein and The Atlantic," The Yale University Library Gazette, vol.28, no.3, (January 1954).; pp.109-120. (Box 5, Folder 9)
    Correspondence between Ellery Sedgwick, editor of The Atlantic Monthly, and Gertrude Stein.
  - "Gertrude Stein talking--A trans-Atlantic interview," UCLA in Review, vol.8, no.2; vol.9, no.1 and 2, (Summer 1962, Spring 1963, Winter 1964).; pp.3-11, 40-48, 44-45. Photocopy. (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - "Gertrude Stein's conquest of the Midwest," Real America, vol.6, no.5, (February 1936).; pp.40-42. (Box 5, Folder 11)
    In this same issue: "James Joyce vs. Gertrude Stein" by Harry Beardsley (pp.43, 76-77).
  - "With Alice B. Toklas," Gourmet, vol.34, no.3, (March 1974).; pp.35-36, 90, 92-95. (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Articles about Gertrude Stein and/or Alice B. Toklas
  - Knickerbocker, William S. "Stunning Stein," Sewanee Review, vol.44, no.4, (October-December 1933).; pp.[498]-499. (Box 5, Folder 13)
    Review of The autobiography of Alice B. Toklas.
  - "Gertrude Stein: the new literature," The Hollins Critic, vol.12, no.3, (June 1975); pp.2-15. (Box 5, Folder 14)
    Reprint.
    Published by Hollins College, Virginia.
    Cover drawing of Stein by Lewis O. Thompson.
  - "Hunter Stagg: 'Over there in Paris with Gertrude Stein," The Ellen Glasgow Newsletter, issue 15, (October 1981).; pp.2-16. (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - "Gertrude Stein: I am I because ... my little dog knows me," The Christian Science Monitor, (February 13, 1971).; p.1. (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - "The artist is also a performer of art," Long Island Press, (April 27, 1975).; p.[1], photocopy. (Box 5, Folder 17)
    re exhibition at C.W. Post Gallery.
  - "Poet's brother," The New Yorker, (March 23, 1935).; p.13, photocopy. (Box 5, Folder 18)
    Anecdote re Leo Stein.
    With this: Leo Stein's reply. Photocopy.
  - "A valentine to Gertrude Stein," Westways, vol.66, no.2, (February 1974).; pp.18-23, 68. (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - "A conversation," The Atlantic, (August 1935).; pp.187-194. Photocopy. (Box 5, Folder 20)
    Gertrude Stein on American writers.
  - "Four patron saints in one act," [New York Times Sunday Magazine?], pp.58-62, 65. Clipping. (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - "Recipes to fit the occasion," Newsday/ Leisure Guide, (April 26, 1975).; pp.2A-. Photocopy. Incomplete. (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - "Display on the world of Gertrude Stein," The New York Times (, April 13, 1975.; pp.[1?]) photocopy. (Box 5, Folder 23)
    re exhibition at C.W. Post Art Gallery.
  - "Has Gertrude Stein, a secret," The Atlantic, (January 1934).; p.57. Photocopy. (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - "Festival a la Stein," Newsday/Leisure Guide, (April 26, 1975).; pp.[1]-2. Photocopy. (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - "And now a bow: a centennial tribute to Gertrude stein," Gazette of the Grolier Club, new series, no.20/21, (June/December 1974).; pp.46-69. (Box 5, Folder 26)
    Cover engraving: Gertrude Stein by Louis Marcoucsis, c1933.
  - Index to articles by and about Stein in The Atlantic. Compiled by Gilbert Harrison[?]., 4 leaves. Photocopy. (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Index to articles by and about Gertrude Stein in The New Yorker. Compiled by Gilbert Harrison[?]., 4 leaves. Photocopy. (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Catalog [for] Gotham Book Mart, 1964.; 1 item. (Box 5, Folder 29)
    Introduction by Carl Van Vechten.
  - Theatre programs and exhibition notices regarding Gertrude Stein. v.p., v.d.; 9 items. (Box 5, Folder 30)
    Includes a copy of Playbill (April 21, 1952) re ANTA production of Four Saints in Three Acts.
- Periodicals
  - The little review, January 1916.; 1 item. Fragile. (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Yale French studies, no.31, (May 1964).; 1 item. (Box 6, Folder 2)
    Issue on surrealism.
  - The New Yorker, October 5, 1946 and September 22, 1975.; 2 items. (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Paris France. New York: Charles Scribner's Sons, 1940.; 1 leaf Typescript with holograph notes. (Box 6, Folder 4)
    With this: Miss Freschl's reminiscences of the war years in France and her association with Gertrude Stein.
    Gift of Lisbeth N. Freschl, 1974.
- Scrapbook
  Includes articles by and about Gertrude Stein and Alice B. Toklas.
  - Notes on lecture by Bernard Fay. "Poetry in the modern world." Claremont, California, October 29, 1936.; 4 leaves Typescript. (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - A primer for the gradual understanding of Gertrude Stein by Robert Bartlett Haas. Los Angeles, August 1965.; Typescript (carbon) and attachments. (Box 8, Folder 2)
    Published Los Angeles, Black Sparrow Press, 1971.
  - Letter to Gilbert Harrison. New York, 9 March 1960.; 1 leaf Typescript (signed). (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Letter to Gilbert Harrison. New York, November 11, 1967.; 2 leaves Typescript (signed). (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - "[Translation of an interview with Gertrude Stein, January 4, 1934. By Hector Ghilini.]" Bilignin, September 9, 1933.; 2 leaves Typescript transcription. (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Scrapbook
  - [No further description available]. (Box 8)
    Includes articles by and about Stein, book reviews, theatre programs re Stein productions, exhibition catalogs. Additions have been made to the collection with funds donated by Mrs. Frederick W. Davis.
- [Additions], v.d.
  Gift of Mrs. Frederick W. Davis.
  - "Crystalized fruit & pastry sketch for Alice B. Toklas's Cook book." n.p., n.d.; Sketch: 10.7 × 17.1 cm. Mount: 18.1 × 26.5 cm. Ink wash. (Box 6, Folder 5)
    A sketch for the Alice B. Toklas Cook Book, New York, Harper & Brothers [c1954], not used in the published work. There is a holograph note on the verso of the sketch signed by Francis Rose.
  - Letter to Sir Francis Rose. Bilignin, August.; 20.8 × 27 cm. 1 item (2 leaves) Holograph. (Box 6, Folder 6)
    Letter to Francis Rose expressing disappointment in a particular picture.
  - Two (hitherto unpublished) poems. n.p., 1921.; 2 leaves Typescript(carbon). With holograph corrections by Carl Van Vechten. (Box 6, Folder 7)
    The poems are titled "Dinner" and "To-day we have a vacation." Published posthumously by The Gotham Book Mart in New York, 1948.
    Purchased from the Banyan Press Archive, 1982.
  - Five or six men. Paris, n.d. [ca. 1908-1912].; t.p., 62pp. Typescript. (Box 6, Folder 8)
    With typing corrections by Alice B. Toklas and holograph corrections by Gertrude Stein.
    Published posthumously in Two: Gertrude Stein and her brother, and other early portraits. New Haven: Yale University Press, 1951.
    Purchase, Sotheby's, April 1982.
  - A man. Paris, n.d. [ca. 1908-1912].; t.p., 21 p. Typescript(carbon). Title page torn, lacking upper right corner. (Box 6, Folder 9)
    Published posthumously in Two: Gertrude Stein and her brother, and other early portraits, New Haven, Yale University Press, 1951.
  - Paris France. New York, Charles Scribner's Sons, 1940.; 120 p. 14.2 × 22.2 cm. Dustjacket. (Box 6, Folder 10)
    Presentation copy from Sir Francis Rose, with inscription on front free endpaper "Don's copy/Souvenir/of/Paris/Francis" with full page water color illustration surrounding Don Rascher's signature and serial number 36637724; water color illustration of the Eiffel Tower signed "Francis Rose/1945"; Pen and ink illustration signed "Francis Rose" on title page; pen and ink illustration under publisher's acknowledgment signed "Francis Rose" with illustration of sun above printed text; pen and ink illustrations above, right and below list of illustrations (vii); pen and ink illustration above Part I, p.1 of text.
    Purchase, ABI Books, May 1982.
  - Letter to "My dear William Alfred." Paris, 16 June 1945.; 1 leaf (2pp.) Holograph. (Box 6, Folder 11)
    William Alfred, apparently a soldier in the American Army, had sent a friend to meet Gertrude Stein. In this letter, she writes of his visit.
    Purchase, Argosy Book Shop, June 1982.
  - Letter to Gilberte Sutherland. Paris, August 8, 1945.; 1 item. (1 leaf/2pp., 1 envelope). Holograph. (Box 6, Folder 12)
    With typed transcription. Gilberte Sutherland was the wife of Donald Sutherland.
    Purchase, B. Hacker, August 1982.
  - Letters to Lynn Martin. Paris, November 1, 1957 and March 10,1958.; 2 items (2 leaves) Holograph. (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Letters to Donald Sutherland. Paris, January 12, 1958 and [November 27, 1958]; 2 items (3 leaves, 2 envelopes). Holograph. (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Letter to M. Tannens and [Pavel] Tchelitchew. Paris, 29 October 1945.; 1 item (1 leaf, 1 envelope). Holograph. (Box 6, Folder 15)
    An invitation to tea and a note of thanks for a drawing. The letter is addressed to "My dear friends" but Tannen has been crossed out on the envelope.
    Purchase, Sotheby's, October 1982.
  - Letters to Robert Carlton Brown. Paris and Bilignin, ca. 1930-1932.; 3 items (1 leaf, 1 envelope, 2 postcards). Holograph. (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - "Remembering Gertrude," Columbia Library Columns, vol.31, no.2, (February 1982).; pp.[2]-17. (Box 6, Folder 17)
    Gift of Jake Zeitlin, October 1982.
  - Letters to Joy Rea. Paris, March-April 1955.; 4 items (7 leaves, 4 envelopes). Holograph. (Box 6, Folder 18)
    Purchase, Swann's Galleries, December 1982.
  - Letters to Joy Rea. Paris, Nice, February-September 1957.; 4 items (10 leaves, 5 envelopes). Holograph. (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Letters to Joy Rea. Paris, Grasse, January-October 1957.; 5 items (10 leaves, 5 envelopes). Holograph. (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Letters to Joy Rea. Paris, Acqui Terme, March-November 1958.; 6 items (13 leaves, 6 envelopes). Holograph. (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Letters to Joy Rea. Paris, St. Maxime, Nice, June-September 1959.; 4 items (1 card, 3 leaves, 3 envelopes), Holograph. (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Letters to Joy Rea. Paris, Rome, Acqui Terme, February-November 1960.; 6 items (13 leaves, 6 envelopes). Holograph. (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Letters to Joy Rea. Paris, Rome, January-October 1961.; 5 items (6 leaves, 2 cards, 4 envelopes). Holograph and manuscript. (Box 6, Folder 24)
    Letters of August 19, 1961 and September 2, 1961 in another hand.
  - Letters to Joy Rea. Paris, Acqui Terme, February-December 1962.; 9 items (11 leaves, 9 envelopes). (Box 6, Folder 25)
    Manuscript.
    All letters dictated to Toklas' secretaries.
  - Letters to Joy Rea. Paris, January-March 1963.; 4 items (6 leaves, 2 cards, 4 envelopes). Holograph. (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Photographs taken by Picasso of two of his portraits, ca. 1904.; 2 items. (Box 6, Folder 27)
    Given to Gertrude Stein and Alice Toklas. Toklas subsequently gave them to Joy Rea.
  - Program for the UCLA Opera Workshop production, The Mother of us all. Los Angeles, May 13-23, 1965. (Box 6, Folder 28)
    Text by Gertrude Stein, music by Virgil Thomson, scenario by Maurice Grosser. Inscribed on the front cover "For Dan/Luckenbill/warmly/Virgil Thomson."
    Gift of Daniel Luckenbill, February 1983.
  - Gertrude Stein. Golfe Juan (France), 7 Mars 1937.; 4 leaves 21 × 26.5 cm. Holograph. (Box 6, Folder 29)
    Manuscript, signed, with corrections. Picabia has numbered the pages.
    With this: Letter from Picabia to "Cher Ami," mentioning Gertrude Stein. Golfe Juan. (France), 7 March 1937. 1 leaf.
    Purchase, Minkoff, 1983.
  - "Memory is all," The New Yorker, (December 1975).; pp.141-154. (Box 6, Folder 30)
    Review of Staying on Alone: Letters of Alice B. Toklas.
    Gift of Dr. & Mrs. Gardner Miller, February 1984.
- Letters to Louise and Redvers Taylor, v.p., 1922-1967.; 183 items. Typescript (carbon).
  These are typescript transcriptions prepared for an edition of Alice Toklas's letters. With the transcriptions is a letter from Edward Burns, who edited the letters, requesting permission to publish the letters, with an inventory of these to be included. The transcriptions are in a dark blue cloth lettercase with leather label.
  Alice B. Toklas to Louise and Redvers Tailor. Letters are addressed to Louise Taylor unless otherwise indicated.
  Purchase, Argosy, 1984.
  - 1922. (Box 7)
    6 August 1922.
  - 1924. (Box 7)
    17 August 1924.
  - 1928. (Box 7)
    10 September 1928.
  - 1946. (Box 7)
    14 August 1946.
    29 September 1946.
    28 October 1946.
    22 and 30 December 1946.
  - 1947. (Box 7)
    7 January 1947.
    20 February 1947.
    14 March 1947.
    10 April 1947.
    1 May 1947.
    2 or 11 June 1947.
    12 July 1947. Louise and Redvers.
    18 August 1947. Louise and Redvers.
    28 December 1947.
  - 1948. (Box 7)
    7 January 1948. Louise and Redvers.
    15, 20 and 28 January.
    21 February 1948. Louise and Redvers.
    25 March 1948.
    30 June 1948.
    22 July 1948. Louise and Redvers.
    4 and 15 September 1948.
    12 December 1948.
  - 1949. (Box 7)
    18 April 1949. Louise and Redvers.
    1 May 1949. Louise and Redvers.
    9 May 1949.
    18 July 1949. Louise and Redvers.
    15 December 1949. Louise and Redvers.
  - 1950. (Box 7)
    31 January 1950.
    31 March 1950.
    15 May 1950.
    3 July 1950.
    [9 September] 1950.
    27 December 1950. Louise and Redvers.
  - 1951. (Box 7)
    23 January 1951.
    11 February 1951.
    6 March 1951.
    18 March 1951.
    2 June 1951. Louise and Redvers.
    27 June 1951.
    8 and 15 July 1951. Louise and Redvers.
    18 August 1951. Louise and Redvers.
    6 October 1951. Louise and Redvers.
  - 1952. (Box 7)
    28 January 1952.
    1 April 1952.
    26 May 1952.
    7 July 1952.
    14 August 1952.
    5 October 1952.
  - 1953. (Box 7)
    2 January 1953.
    14 March 1953.
    15 April 1953. Louise and Redvers.
    23 April 1953.
    1 June 1953. Louise and Redvers.
    3 June 1953. Louise and Redvers.
    1 June 1953.
    24 August 1953.
    28 November 1953. Louise and Redvers.
    8 December 1953. Louise and Redvers.
    29 December 1953. Louise and Redvers.
  - 1954. (Box 7)
    28 January 1954.
    13 February 1954. Louise and Redvers.
    23 March 1954.
    30-31 May 1954. Louise and Redvers.
    5 June 1954.
    17 June 1954. Louise and Redvers.
    7 July 1954. Louise and Redvers.
    18 and 24 July 1954.
    12 and 19 September 1954.
    18 and 24 November 1954.
    [1954?].
  - 1955. (Box 7)
    20 and 31 January 1955.
    [January-February 1955?].
    24 February 1955.
    15 March 1955.
    27 April 1955.
    26 June 1955.
    [7] and 13 August 1955.
    7 September 1955.
    11 December 1955. Louise and Redvers.
    [1955]. Redvers (2 letters).
  - 1956. (Box 7)
    ?? January 1956.
    6 February 1956.
    14 April 1956.
    3 July 1956. Louise and Redvers.
    10 August 1956.
    20 September 1956.
    11 December 1956. Louise and Redvers.
    31 December 1956.
  - 1957. (Box 7)
    2 March, 8 and 13 April 1957. Louise and Redvers.
    12 July 1957. Louise and Redvers.
    23 December 1957. Louise and Redvers.
    [1957]. Louise and Redvers.
    [1957?].
  - 1958. (Box 7)
    8 March and 13 July 1958. Louise and Redvers.
    20 September 1958. Louise and Redvers.
    21 September 1958. Louise and Redvers.
    28 October 1958. Louise and Redvers.
    [1958?]. Louise and Redvers.
  - 1959. (Box 7)
    15 January 1959. Louise and Redvers.
    28 June, 6, 11 and 27 July 1959. Louise and Redvers.
    23 August, 20 and 25 November 1959. Louise and Redvers.
    [November 1959?]. Louise and Redvers.
    5 December 1959. Louise and Redvers.
    29 December 1959. Louise and Redvers.
  - 1960. (Box 7)
    23 March 1960. Louise and Redvers.
    6 June 1960. Louise and Redvers.
    9 July 1960. Louise and Redvers.
    5 August 1960. Louise and Redvers.
    25 October 1960. Louise and Redvers.
  - 1961. (Box 7)
    2 January 1961.
    15 February 1961. Louise and Redvers.
    10 March 1961. Louise and Redvers.
    7 May 1961. Louise and Redvers.
    6 August 1961. Louise and Redvers.
    13 August 1961. Louise and Redvers.
    8 September 1961. Louise and Redvers.
    10 October 1961. Louise and Redvers.
    14 October 1961.
    15 October 1961. Louise and Redvers.
    31 October 1961. Louise and Redvers.
    November 1961.
    21 November 1961.
    [1961]. Louise and Redvers.
  - 1962. (Box 7)
    9 January 1962. Louise and Redvers.
    25 March 1962. Louise and Redvers.
    9 May 1962. Louise and Redvers.
    13 May 1962. Louise and Redvers.
    30 May 1962. Redvers.
    30 May 1962.
    13 June 1962.
    16 June 1962.
    15 July 1962. Louise and Redvers.
    3 August 1962. Louise and Redvers.
    5 August 1962. Louise and Redvers.
    7 August 1962. Louise and Redvers.
    11 August 1962.
    27 August 1962. Louise and Redvers.
    [2] September 1962.
    5 December 1962. Louise and Redvers.
    27 December 1962. Louise and Redvers.
  - 1963. (Box 7)
    February 1963. Louise and Redvers.
    23 March 1963. Louise and Redvers.
    24 March 1963. Louise and Redvers.
    22 April 1963. Louise and Redvers.
    25 May 1963. Louise and Redvers.
    28 May 1963. Louise and Redvers.
    21 August 1963. Louise and Redvers.
    24 September 1963. Louise and Redvers.
    [1963]. Louise and Redvers.
    [1963?]. Louise and Redvers.
  - 1964. (Box 7)
    [1964]. Louise and Redvers.
  - 1965. (Box 7)
    3 January [1965]. Louise and Redvers.
    28 February [1965]. Louise and Redvers.
    26 April [1965]. Louise and Redvers.
    [5 June [1965]]. Louise and Redvers.
    27 July [1965]. Louise and Redvers.
  - 1966. (Box 7)
    17 March [1966]. Louise and Redvers.
    14 April [1966]. Louise and Redvers.
  - 1967. (Box 7)
    10 January 1967. Louise and Redvers.
    n.d. Louise and Redvers.
- Bilignin Sketch book, Bilignin, 1972.; 1 item. 21cm. × 27 cm. (Box 7, Folder 2)
  Signed Francis Rose, June 1932 as front cover.
  Includes sketches of Gertrude's hands, Alice's iron chair, Alice's hands, Bernard Fay, Pierre Balmain, chalk sketch of Alice B. Toklas laid in, Robert Desnos, figure studies.
  Purchase, Boyle Galleries, 1989.
- [Sketchbook]. [Paris, 1946]., 1 item. 11.5 cm. × 16.5 cm. The spine of the sketchbook is broken. (Box 7, Folder 2)
  14 numbered pencil sketches of Gertrude Stein and Alice P. Toklas.
  Francis Rose as noted on the front endeavor that "These are probable the last drawings Gertrude Stein by him on his last visit to The Christine."
  Purchase, Doyle Galleries, 1984.
- [Card to Allan Tanner and Pavel Tchelitchew]. [Paris, ]., 1928; 1 item. Holograph. With envelope. (Box 7, Folder 3)
  Transcription available.
  Purchase, Doris Harris, June 1984.
- [Card to Allan Tanner and Pavel Tchelitchew, postmarked 1928]., [Embossed letterhead]: "Rose is a rose is a rose is a rose." (Box 7, Folder 3)
  27 Rue De Fleurus / "My dear Allan & Pavion, / So sorry to have missed / You again the other day, come / In Saturday evening do both of you......"
  p.2: "We will be at home then and ver / glad to see you. / Always / Gtde."
- Letter to Georges Hugnet, Larchmont, New York., 1 item. Typescript signed. (Box 7, Folder 4)
  Letter enclosing payment for Hugnet's tribute to Miss Stein which appeared in Morrow's Almanach for 1929.
  Removed from a copy of Morrow's Almanach.
  Purchase, George Houle, July 1984.
- Letters to Lloyd Lewis. v.p., []., ca. 1935-1939; 4 items. Holograph. (Box 7, Folder 5)
  Regarding Lewis's book, Myths after Lincoln, occupation of her home by the French Army, and personal news.
  Letter of 18 November 1947 is from Alice B. Toklas.
  Transcriptions available.
  Purchase, Argosy, September 1984.
- [Broadside for] Judith Martin and Dance Company... in the first performance of The World is Round ... based on the book by Gertrude Stein ... New York, []., ca. 1946; 1 item. 24.5 × 20.5 cm. Printed. Navy blue and Orange/pink printed on white. (Box 7, Folder 6)
  Purchase, Black Sun Books, 1984.
- "And so. To change so. (A fantasy on three careers)." n.p., 7 leaves. Typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 7, Folder 7)
  This was published in Portraits and Prayers (New York Random House, 1934). Stein's name and address. 27 rue de Fleurus, are typed in the upper left corner.
  Purchase, Zeitlin & Ver Brugge, 1983.
- Letters to William Cook (an American Stein met in Majorca). v.p., v.d.; 7 items, Holograph. (Box 7, Folder 8)
  Purchase, Sotheby's, December 1984.
- Letter to Anita Loos. Paris, 14 July 1958.; 1 item. Autograph letter (signed). (Box 7, Folder 9)
  Toklas thanks Loos for her visit, gift of roses, and discusses a trip to the baths at Cegni.
  Purchase, George Houle, 1985.
- Letters to Anita Loos. v.p., 1958-1967.; 19 items. Holograph, manuscript, typescript (carbon). (Box 7, Folder 10)
  All items have transcriptions.
  1) 5 Rue Christine, Paris, 14 June 1958. 1 leaf (1p.) Carbon transcription only.
  2) 5 Rue Christine, Paris, 26 March 1958. 1 1eaf (1p.) Autograph letter (signed).
  3) 5 Rue Christine, Paris, 19 November 1958. 1 1eaf (1p.) Autograph letter (signed).
  4) 5 Rue Christine, Paris, [1962?] 1 leaf (1p.) Carbon transcription only.
  5) 5 Rue Christine, Paris [1962?] 1 leaf (1p.) Manuscript. written for Toklas by her secretary.
  6) 5 Rue Christine, Paris, 20 February 1962, 2 leaves (2pp.) Manuscript. Written for Toklas by her secretary.
  7) 5 Rue Christine, Paris, 19 March 1962, 2 leaves (2pp.) Manuscript. Written for Toklas by her secretary, Signed J.B. in lower left corner of p.2.
  8) 5 Rue Christine, Paris [1962?] 1 leaf (1p.) Carbon transcription only.
  9) 5 Rue Christine, Paris [1962?] 1 leaf (1p.) Carbon transcription only.
  10) n.p. [1963?] 1 leaf (1p.) Manuscript cars written for Toklas by her secretary.
  11) Rue Christine, 24 April 1963, 2 leaves (2pp.) Single. With mention of a visit by Donald Sutherlane.
  12) 5 Rue Christine, 21 March, 1963, 1 leaf (1p.)
  13) n.p. [1964?] Manuscript cars written for Toklas by her secretary.
  14) 16, Rue De La Convention, Paris [1965?] 1 leaf (1p.) Autograph letter (signed).
  15) 16, Rue De La Convention, Paris, 8 November [1965?] 1 leaf (1p.) Manuscript letter written for Toklas by her secretary, signed by Toklas.
  16) 16, Rue De La Convention, Paris, [1966?] 1 leaf ( 1p.) Manuscript, Written for Toklas by her Secretary.
  17) 16, Rue De La Convention, Paris, 7 March [1966?] 1 leaf (1p.) Manuscript. Written for Toklas by her secretary.
  18) 16, Rue De La Convention, Paris, 29 April [1966?] 1 leaf (1p.) Manuscript. Written for Toklas by her secretary.
  19) n.p. 2 January 1967 1 leaf ( 1p.) Manuscript letter written for Toklas by her secretary, signed by Toklas.
  Items 1, 4, 8 and 9 have transcriptions only.
  Purchase, Houie, 1985.
- "Brewsle and Willie," n.p., ca. 1945-46[?].; 61pp. Typescript (carbon) and typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 7, Folder 11)
  This is a carbon typescript with corrections by Stein. There are 2 copies of p.61, original and carbon, both with corrections.